Guide to the Harry T. Hamilton, Class of 1904, Yale College, Memorabilia
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harry T. Hamilton, Class of 1904, Yale College, memorabilia
1889-1943
RU 897
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(2 boxes)
The materials consist of a scrapbook,photographs, a calendar celebrating Yale's 1901 bicentennial, the Class of 1901's valedictory poem and oration, and other assorted printed materials documenting Harry T. Hamilton's (Yale 1904) life as a student at Yale. Included is a memoir by Henry Bancroft Twombly, a Yale football player, and an edition of Yale, A Record of the Dinner, February 16, 1889.
Harry Thomas Hamilton, 1880-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 45 (YRG 45), Yale objects and memorabilia.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were donated by Richard Hamilton, 2001, and Ann B. Hamilton, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The memorabilia is arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of a scrapbook, photographs, a calendar celebrating Yale's 1901 bicentennial, the Class of 1901's valedictory poem and oration, and other assorted printed materials documenting Harry T. Hamilton's (Yale 1904) life as a student at Yale. Included is a memoir by Henry Bancroft Twombly, a Yale football player, and an edition of Yale, A Record of the Dinner, February 16, 1889.
Football; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Hamilton, Harry Thomas, 1880-; Twombly, Henry Bancroft, 1862-; Yale University -- Football; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Scrapbook and memorabilia of Harry Thomas Hamilton (1904), 1889-1943; Accession 2002-A-119
  - Printed materials documenting Harry T. Hamilton's (Yale 1904) life as a student of Yale, 1889, 1901, 1939, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calendars, 1901
    - Yale's bicentennial (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1903 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1879-1905 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Photographs, Circa 1902-1919; Accession 2011-A-054
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon group photographs, 1902-circa 1904 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Freshman baseball team, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hamilton's student room, Circa 1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Quindecennial reunion group photograph in front of Woodbridge Hall, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Unidentified student group, Circa 1902 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    General
    Probably either DKE or Elihu; Hamilton was a member of both.